<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Modelling | Nils Rottmann | Homepage</title>
    <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/tags/modelling/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://nrottmann.github.io/tags/modelling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Modelling</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://nrottmann.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Modelling</title>
      <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/tags/modelling/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Localizsation and Control for Trajectory Tracking for Autonomous Lawn Mowers</title>
      <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/thesis/ricoklinckenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nrottmann.github.io/thesis/ricoklinckenberg/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The present bachelor thesis presents the necessary methods for an exact selflocalization by using an Inertial Mesurment Unit (IMU) and the odometry of an
autonomous lawn mower. This self-localization shall be used in later work together
with a localization of a particle filter. The required standard models [12] for the
individual sensor systems were examined and the required parameters determined.
Measurements were taken with the autonomous lawn mower to develop a Kalman
filter [15] based on the data obtained. With the help of the Kalman filter and
a controller which was designed in this thesis, such a self-localization could be
realized. The results show that the autonomous lawnmower can locate itself under
simulated conditions with a higher accuracy than with a pure localization via
odometry. However, final measurements show that disturbances of the IMU occur
within the autonomous lawn mower, so that a final overall behaviour cannot be
implemented with the current architecture of the autonomous lawn mower.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
