<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mobile Robotics | Nils Rottmann | Homepage</title>
    <link>/tags/mobile-robotics/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/mobile-robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Mobile Robotics</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Mobile Robotics</title>
      <link>/tags/mobile-robotics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>ROS-Mobile</title>
      <link>/project/ros_mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/ros_mobile/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous Localization and Mapping with Room Labeling</title>
      <link>/thesis/nicostudt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/thesis/nicostudt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The focus of this work is on extending the functionality of the robot platform
Loomo. Using cartography and navigation methods, the basis for an autonomous system is created. In addition, the recognition and storage of AR
markers simplifies human-robot interaction by enabling targeted navigation
to specific locations. The implementation of the used software components
ROS, Movebase, RTAB-Map and ALVAR is described in detail and tested in
an experimental setting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complete coverage path planning for low cost robots</title>
      <link>/thesis/robindenz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/thesis/robindenz/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The demand among the population for household robots continues to rise.
These include in particular mobile cleaning and lawn mowing robots. These
are usually very expensive and still very inefficient. Especially for lawn mowing robots, it is essential to have visited the entire working space in order to
perform their task correctly. However, the current state of the art is still random walk algorithms, which are very unreliable and inefficient. The present
bachelor thesis therefore presents a method for intelligent path planning for
mobile &amp;ldquo;low cost&amp;rdquo;robots using a lawn mower robot. The robot is only equipped
with binary sensors to detect its position in its working space, which is fraught
with high uncertainties. By an intelligent representation of the already visited
working space as well as the path planning inspired by neural networks, the
lawn mower robot manages to achieve a decisive improvement in efficiency
compared to the random walk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIRANA - A mobile robotic assistant</title>
      <link>/talk/nook2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/nook2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L端becker Nachrichten reports about MIRANA</title>
      <link>/post/ln_article/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/ln_article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The L端becker Nachrichten reports about robots in everyday life: digital helpers are available at UKSH. Our MIRANA project is also part of it. Have a look whole report &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ln-online.de/Nachrichten/Norddeutschland/Roboter-im-Klinik-Alltag-am-UKSH-Luebeck-So-fortschrittlich-sind-Krankenhaeuser-im-Norden&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UKSH Opening, L端beck</title>
      <link>/post/ukshopening/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/ukshopening/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The opening of the USKH in L端beck was a nice event where we had again the opportunity to present our MIRANA robot. The opening was together with an open house day, which gave us the opportunity to directly test on how MIRANA resonates with the potential patientes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autumn School</title>
      <link>/talk/autumnschool2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/autumnschool2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare Hackathon Kiel - MIRANA Introduction</title>
      <link>/talk/hhkiel2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 12:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/hhkiel2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loop Closure Detection in Closed Environments</title>
      <link>/publication/ecmr2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/ecmr2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare Hackathon Berlin Speech</title>
      <link>/talk/hhberlin2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 12:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/hhberlin2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Common Future</title>
      <link>/project/legorobots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/legorobots/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ROS-Gazebo Tutorial</title>
      <link>/tutorials/rosgazebo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/tutorials/rosgazebo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIRANA</title>
      <link>/project/mirana/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/mirana/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think at IBM</title>
      <link>/talk/thinkatibm2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 12:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/thinkatibm2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cataglyphis ant navigation strategies solve the global localization problem in robots with binary sensors</title>
      <link>/publication/biosignals2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/biosignals2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trajectory planning for mobile robots for working area complete coverage under high uncertainty</title>
      <link>/thesis/alexanderosiik/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/thesis/alexanderosiik/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Bachelor thesis presents an approach for the complete coverage path
planning (CCPP) problem which occurs for different robotic applications, such
as autonomous lawn mowers or vaccuum cleaners. Methods used for localization
[27], map representation [10] and planning [14] are discussed under consideration
of sensor noise and uncertainty about the own position induced by the movement
of the robot. An efficient method to solve the CCPP problem under uncertainty is
proposed and evaluated due to simulations. The results show that under simulated
conditions, the autonomous lawnmower covers the field of work faster and
can guarantee complete coverage, in contrast to commercially used techniques.
Furthermore, an efficient algorithm to divide the working area into smaller areas
is developed, which leads to an increased computational and storage efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of a chlorophyll-sensor for mowing-area-detection for autonomous lawn mowers</title>
      <link>/thesis/friedrichpodstawa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/thesis/friedrichpodstawa/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make it easier for people to work in the lawn care, there is a long list of robotic lawnmowers. The navigation is a big problem, since the application is usually limited by a perimeter wire. This process means a time as well as financial expense and must be changed. For this purpose, a new method for lawn detection was developed at the Institute of Robotics and Cognitive Systems. A hardware that measures a parameter characteristic of turf plants by optically stimulating chlorophyll synthesis and measuring the resulting chlorophyll fluorescence, and safely distinguishes turf plants from non-organic material has been designed. In this thesis, this sensor system will be further developed into a product-related prototype. The mowing area detection is significantly improved by optimizing the
sensor under different lighting conditions. Furthermore, the functionality of an
existing robotic lawnmower system, which will be equipped with the new sensor
system, will be retained. This should reliably be able to drive over a lawn without
leaving it.
Tests show that the mowing area detection was significantly improved with the
help of the chlorophyll fluorescence sensor. The sensor is thus suitable for outdoor
use. Sensor hardware and software have been transferred from a field-less system
to a perfectly functioning mower surface detection sensor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Localizsation and Control for Trajectory Tracking for Autonomous Lawn Mowers</title>
      <link>/thesis/ricoklinckenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/thesis/ricoklinckenberg/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The present bachelor thesis presents the necessary methods for an exact selflocalization by using an Inertial Mesurment Unit (IMU) and the odometry of an
autonomous lawn mower. This self-localization shall be used in later work together
with a localization of a particle filter. The required standard models [12] for the
individual sensor systems were examined and the required parameters determined.
Measurements were taken with the autonomous lawn mower to develop a Kalman
filter [15] based on the data obtained. With the help of the Kalman filter and
a controller which was designed in this thesis, such a self-localization could be
realized. The results show that the autonomous lawnmower can locate itself under
simulated conditions with a higher accuracy than with a pure localization via
odometry. However, final measurements show that disturbances of the IMU occur
within the autonomous lawn mower, so that a final overall behaviour cannot be
implemented with the current architecture of the autonomous lawn mower.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous Localization and Mapping for Autonomous Lawn Mowers</title>
      <link>/thesis/svenandresen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/thesis/svenandresen/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
