<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leander Busch | Nils Rottmann | Homepage</title>
    <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/authors/leander-busch/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://nrottmann.github.io/authors/leander-busch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Leander Busch</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://nrottmann.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Leander Busch</title>
      <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/authors/leander-busch/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Motion Models for Local Path Planning Strategies</title>
      <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/thesis/leanderbusch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nrottmann.github.io/thesis/leanderbusch/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Segway Loomo is a self-balancing segway robot, which is constantly balanced
by an internal control system. A local path planning strategy was developed in
advance for this robot. For local path planning, a motion model of the robot
is needed to determine the effect of velocity commands on the robot’s pose. In
the implemented local path planner, a simple motion model of the robot is used,
which does not model the effect of the segway robot’s internal control on its
motion. In this work, it was investigated whether a more accurate motion model
for the Segway Loomo robot can be learned by using artificial neural networks
to improve the local path planning for this robot. For this purpose, different
architectures of feedforward networks were tested. The neural networks were
trained and evaluated using recorded motion data of the segway robot. The
best learned model was validated by using a standard differential drive motion
model as a reference. For the validation of the learned model, the accuracy of
both motion models was examined on the recorded motion data. On average,
the learned model is 59.48 % more accurate in determining the position of the
robot at the next time step and 24.61 % more accurate in determining the new
orientation of the robot than the differential drive motion model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
