<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning | Nils Rottmann | Homepage</title>
    <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/tags/machine-learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://nrottmann.github.io/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Machine Learning</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://nrottmann.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Motion Models for Local Path Planning Strategies</title>
      <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/thesis/leanderbusch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nrottmann.github.io/thesis/leanderbusch/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Segway Loomo is a self-balancing segway robot, which is constantly balanced
by an internal control system. A local path planning strategy was developed in
advance for this robot. For local path planning, a motion model of the robot
is needed to determine the effect of velocity commands on the robot’s pose. In
the implemented local path planner, a simple motion model of the robot is used,
which does not model the effect of the segway robot’s internal control on its
motion. In this work, it was investigated whether a more accurate motion model
for the Segway Loomo robot can be learned by using artificial neural networks
to improve the local path planning for this robot. For this purpose, different
architectures of feedforward networks were tested. The neural networks were
trained and evaluated using recorded motion data of the segway robot. The
best learned model was validated by using a standard differential drive motion
model as a reference. For the validation of the learned model, the accuracy of
both motion models was examined on the recorded motion data. On average,
the learned model is 59.48 % more accurate in determining the position of the
robot at the next time step and 24.61 % more accurate in determining the new
orientation of the robot than the differential drive motion model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plant Classification based on Chlorophyll Detection for autonomous Gardening</title>
      <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/thesis/janphilipklose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nrottmann.github.io/thesis/janphilipklose/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon illumination of a sufficient amount of light, the chlorophyll molecules of
a plant start to emit photons in the far red region of the light spectrum. This
phenomenon is also known as chlorophyll fluorescence. In this thesis a classi-
fier is built that serves as a benchmark for plant classification via chlorophyll a
fluorescence. A data set of 2500 samples was acquired by illuminating a total
of 500 leaves gathered from five different plants with seven LEDs. To achieve
an optimal model, a convolutional neural network (CNN) was designed and
trained on complete fluorescence spectra. The network achieved an average
accuracy of 95,7% on classifying five plants. Furthermore, the networks ac-
curacy on a smaller set of LEDs was tested. In the end, a low cost approach
was trained and evaluated, reaching an accuracy of 68%. This approach uses
simulated phototransistor data instead of full spectra acquired with a spec-
trometer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/tutorials/pml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nrottmann.github.io/tutorials/pml/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for plant classification based on chlorophyll detection</title>
      <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/thesis/alexanderwalter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nrottmann.github.io/thesis/alexanderwalter/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the intention to build an autonomous lawn mower robot, this work
examines the viability of a sensor and microprocessor for onboard plant clas-
sification using machine learning. Usually, some sort of fencing is required to
keep the robot in its intended processing area, so such a sensor would allow
the robot to differentiate between grass and e.g. flowers. Also, the drive and
blade speed can be adjusted for certain species or plant densities, etc.
For this, a data set was collected utilizing a specific method called chloro-
phyll fluorescence induction. A series of narrowband LEDs are used to drive
this process, while a spectrometer measures the spectral intensity. The plant
will fluoresce in specific wavelengths when sufficiantly illuminated. With this
data, machine learning algorithms are trained to explore if they are capable
to classify these plants without further information.
With accuracies up to 98% for three plants commonly present on a lawn
and up to 86% for eight plants, the results show that chlorophyll fluorescence
is a viable method for classification, even under sunlight using the random
forest machine learning algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
