<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Planning | Nils Rottmann | Homepage</title>
    <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/tags/planning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://nrottmann.github.io/tags/planning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Planning</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://nrottmann.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Planning</title>
      <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/tags/planning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A-DRZ</title>
      <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/project/a_drz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nrottmann.github.io/project/a_drz/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous Localization and Mapping with Room Labeling</title>
      <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/thesis/nicostudt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nrottmann.github.io/thesis/nicostudt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The focus of this work is on extending the functionality of the robot platform
Loomo. Using cartography and navigation methods, the basis for an autonomous system is created. In addition, the recognition and storage of AR
markers simplifies human-robot interaction by enabling targeted navigation
to specific locations. The implementation of the used software components
ROS, Movebase, RTAB-Map and ALVAR is described in detail and tested in
an experimental setting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complete coverage path planning for low cost robots</title>
      <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/thesis/robindenz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nrottmann.github.io/thesis/robindenz/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The demand among the population for household robots continues to rise.
These include in particular mobile cleaning and lawn mowing robots. These
are usually very expensive and still very inefficient. Especially for lawn mowing robots, it is essential to have visited the entire working space in order to
perform their task correctly. However, the current state of the art is still random walk algorithms, which are very unreliable and inefficient. The present
bachelor thesis therefore presents a method for intelligent path planning for
mobile &amp;ldquo;low cost&amp;rdquo;robots using a lawn mower robot. The robot is only equipped
with binary sensors to detect its position in its working space, which is fraught
with high uncertainties. By an intelligent representation of the already visited
working space as well as the path planning inspired by neural networks, the
lawn mower robot manages to achieve a decisive improvement in efficiency
compared to the random walk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare Hackathon Kiel - MIRANA Introduction</title>
      <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/talk/hhkiel2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 12:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nrottmann.github.io/talk/hhkiel2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think at IBM</title>
      <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/talk/thinkatibm2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 12:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nrottmann.github.io/talk/thinkatibm2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trajectory planning for mobile robots for working area complete coverage under high uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/thesis/alexanderosiik/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nrottmann.github.io/thesis/alexanderosiik/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Bachelor thesis presents an approach for the complete coverage path
planning (CCPP) problem which occurs for different robotic applications, such
as autonomous lawn mowers or vaccuum cleaners. Methods used for localization
[27], map representation [10] and planning [14] are discussed under consideration
of sensor noise and uncertainty about the own position induced by the movement
of the robot. An efficient method to solve the CCPP problem under uncertainty is
proposed and evaluated due to simulations. The results show that under simulated
conditions, the autonomous lawnmower covers the field of work faster and
can guarantee complete coverage, in contrast to commercially used techniques.
Furthermore, an efficient algorithm to divide the working area into smaller areas
is developed, which leads to an increased computational and storage efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
