<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Friedrich Podstawa | Nils Rottmann | Homepage</title>
    <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/authors/friedrich-podstawa/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://nrottmann.github.io/authors/friedrich-podstawa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Friedrich Podstawa</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://nrottmann.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Friedrich Podstawa</title>
      <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/authors/friedrich-podstawa/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of a chlorophyll-sensor for mowing-area-detection for autonomous lawn mowers</title>
      <link>https://nrottmann.github.io/thesis/friedrichpodstawa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nrottmann.github.io/thesis/friedrichpodstawa/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make it easier for people to work in the lawn care, there is a long list of robotic lawnmowers. The navigation is a big problem, since the application is usually limited by a perimeter wire. This process means a time as well as financial expense and must be changed. For this purpose, a new method for lawn detection was developed at the Institute of Robotics and Cognitive Systems. A hardware that measures a parameter characteristic of turf plants by optically stimulating chlorophyll synthesis and measuring the resulting chlorophyll fluorescence, and safely distinguishes turf plants from non-organic material has been designed. In this thesis, this sensor system will be further developed into a product-related prototype. The mowing area detection is significantly improved by optimizing the
sensor under different lighting conditions. Furthermore, the functionality of an
existing robotic lawnmower system, which will be equipped with the new sensor
system, will be retained. This should reliably be able to drive over a lawn without
leaving it.
Tests show that the mowing area detection was significantly improved with the
help of the chlorophyll fluorescence sensor. The sensor is thus suitable for outdoor
use. Sensor hardware and software have been transferred from a field-less system
to a perfectly functioning mower surface detection sensor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
